Register of the Karl August Wittfogel papers, 1728-1992
Hoover Institution Archives
- East Asia. See Far East
  - Klatt, Milli (Folder 12)
  - Korea (Folder 13-14)
  - Korean War, 1950-1953 (Box 212, Folder 1-2)
  - Korsch, Karl (Folder 3)
  - Kosener Congress (Folder 4)
  - Kronshtadt Uprising, March 1921 (Folder 5)
  - Kropotkin, Prince Peter
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Writings (Folder 7)
  - Labin, Suzanne (Folder 8)
  - Labor
    - General (Folder 9)
    - China
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Pan Pacific Trade Union. Includes The Pan-Pacific Worker (Folder 11)
    - Germany (Box 213, Folder 1)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 2)
    - United States (Folder 3)
  - Lamennais, Felicite de (Folder 4)
  - Latin America
    - General (Folder 5-6)
    - Clippings (Folder 7)
  - Lattimore, Owen (Folder 8-11)
  - Lattimore, Owen (Box 214, Folder 1-4)
  - League Against Imperialism (Folder 5)
  - League for Industrial Democracy (Folder 6)
  - League of Nations (Folder 7)
  - Lebanon (Folder 8)
  - Lenin, Vladimir Illich
    - General (Folder 9-10)
    - Writings (Folder 11-12)
  - Leninism (Box 215, Folder 1)
  - Liberty (Folder 2)
  - Libraries
    - China (Folder 3)
    - Turkey (Folder 4)
  - Lichtheim, George (Folder 5)
  - Lin Piao - Writings (Folder 6)
  - Literature
    - General (Folder 7)
    - China (Folder 8-9)
    - Germany
      - General (Folder 10-11)
      - Goethe, J. W. von (Box 216, Folder 1)
    - India (Folder 2)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 3)
  - Lithuania (Folder 4)
  - Louis Philippe (Folder 5)
  - Lovestone, Jay - International Communist Summit Conference, 1960 (Folder 6)
  - Lowes, Adolph (Folder 7)
  - Lukacs, Gyorgy (Folder 8)
  - Luneburg (Folder 9-10)
  - Maas, Walther (Folder 11)
  - Magna Carta (Folder 12)
  - Manchuria (Folder 13-14)
  - Manichaeism (Box 217, Folder 1)
  - Mao Tse-tung
    - General (Folder 2-4)
    - Speeches and writings (Folder 5-6)
  - Maoism (Folder 7)
  - Maps
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Australia (Folder 9)
    - Central America (Box 218, Folder 1)
    - China (Folder 2)
    - Germany (Folder 3)
    - Mexico (Folder 4)
    - Middle East (Folder 5)
  - Marathon Group (Folder 6)
  - Marx, Karl
    - General (Folder 7)
    - General (Box 219, Folder 1-6)
    - Writings (Folder 7)
    - Writings by Marx and Engels (Box 220, Folder 1-2)
  - Marxism (Folder 3-7)
  - Mead, Margaret (Box 221, Folder 1)
  - Media
    - General (Folder 2)
    - China (Folder 3)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 4)
  - Mehring, Franz (Folder 5)
  - Mendel, Gregor (Folder 6)
  - Menges, Karl H. See also Etymology for writings by Menges (Folder 7)
  - Mensenburg, Mathilda von (Folder 8)
  - Mexico
    - General (Folder 9)
    - History (Folder 10)
  - Michel, Louise (Folder 11)
  - Middle East (Folder 12-13)
  - Military
    - General (Folder 14)
    - China (Box 222, Folder 1-2)
    - Germany - Reichswehr, 1921-1935 (Folder 3)
    - Great Britain (Folder 4)
    - Japan (Folder 5)
    - Middle East (Folder 6)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 7)
    - Taiwan (Folder 8)
  - Mongolia (Folder 9-10)
  - Morocco (Folder 11)
  - Most, Johann (Folder 12)
  - Namibia (Folder 13)
  - Narodnyi Kommissariat Vnutrennikh del (NKVD) (Folder 14)
  - National Conference on the Study of World Areas, Second (Box 223, Folder 1)
  - National Council of Scholars (Folder 2)
  - Nationalism (Folder 3)
  - Nechaev, Sergei. See also Bakunin, Michael (Folder 4)
  - Netherlands (Folder 5)
  - Nettlau, Max (Folder 6)
  - New America (Folder 7)
  - New Solidarity (Folder 8)
  - New York Daily Tribune (Folder 9)
  - Nietzsche (Folder 10)
  - Nigeria (Folder 11)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (Folder 12)
  - Norman, Herbert (Folder 13)
  - Nuclear strategy
    - China (Folder 14)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 15)
    - United States (Folder 16)
  - O'Neill, Eugene (Folder 17)
  - Organization of American States (OAS) (Folder 18)
  - Oschilewski, Walther G. (Box 224, Folder 1)
  - Ossietzky, Carl von (Folder 2)
  - Owen, Robert (Folder 3)
  - Paetel, Karl O. (Folder 4)
  - Partiia Sotsialistov-Revoliutsionerov (SRP) (Folder 5)
  - Partito Socialista Italiano (Folder 6)
  - Parvus, Alexander Helphand (Folder 7)
  - Pelliot, Paul (Folder 8)
  - Peru (Folder 9)
  - Philosophy
    - General (Folder 10-12)
    - China
      - General (Box 225, Folder 1)
      - Confucius (Folder 2-3)
      - Lao-tzu (Folder 4)
      - Neo-Confucian (Folder 5)
    - Europe
      - Comte, Auguste (Folder 6)
      - Spinoza, Benedict de (Folder 7)
      - Venturi, Franco (Folder 8)
    - Japan (Folder 9)
  - Philippines (Folder 10)
  - Photography (Folder 11)
  - Planck, Max - Writings (Box 226, Folder 1)
  - Plekhanov, Georgii
    - General (Folder 2-3)
    - Writings (Folder 4)
  - Poland
    - General (Folder 5)
    - History (Folder 6)
  - Political geography (Folder 7)
  - Political parties (Folder 8)
  - Political economy (Folder 9)
  - Political theory (Folder 10)
  - Political theory (Box 227, Folder 1-3)
  - Portugal (Folder 4)
  - Praja Socialist Party (India) (Folder 5-6)
  - Prisoners (political and war)
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Japan (Folder 8)
    - United States (Folder 9)
  - Pritsak, Omeljan (Folder 10)
  - Propaganda
    - General (Folder 11)
    - Soviet Union (Box 228, Folder 1)
  - Psychiatry (Folder 2)
  - Psychology (Folder 3-4)
  - Radek, Karl (Folder 5)
  - Radicalism - United States (Folder 6)
  - Railways - China (Folder 7)
  - Reagan, Ronald (Folder 8)
  - Regler, Gustav (Folder 9)
  - Religion
    - General (Folder 10)
    - Asia (Folder 11)
    - China (Folder 12)
    - Germany - Third Reich (Folder 13)
    - India (Folder 14)
    - Soviet Union (Box 229, Folder 1)
    - Tibet (Folder 2)
    - United States (Folder 3)
  - Rhodesia (Folder 4)
  - Ricardo, David (Folder 5)
  - Rockel, August (Folder 6)
  - Roman Empire (Folder 7)
  - Romania (Folder 8)
  - Rossiiskaia Sotsial-Demokraticheskaia Rabochaia Partiia (RSDRP) (Folder 9)
  - Rubin, Vitali (Folder 10)
  - Ruge, Arnold - Writings (Folder 11)
  - Saint Simonism (Folder 12)
  - Schliewen, Rolf (Folder 13)
  - Schmidt, Arno (Folder 14)
  - Schmitt, Erich (Folder 15)
  - Science
    - General (Folder 16)
    - Atomic (Folder 17)
    - China (Folder 18)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 19)
  - Shachtman, Max (Folder 20)
  - Shri Lanka. See Ceylon
  - Sino-American Amity, Inc. (Folder 21)
  - Slavery
    - General (Box 230, Folder 1)
    - China (Folder 2)
  - Smith, Adam - Writings (Folder 3)
  - Snow, Edgar (Folder 4)
  - Social democratic parties
    - Austria (Folder 5)
    - Federal Republic of Germany (Folder 6)
    - Japan (Folder 7)
  - Socialism
    - Nineteenth century
      - General (Folder 8)
      - France (Folder 9)
      - Russia (Folder 10-12)
    - Twentieth century
      - General (Box 231, Folder 1)
      - Poland (Folder 2)
      - Russia/Soviet Union (Folder 3)
      - United States (Folder 4)
  - Sociology
    - General (Folder 5-9)
    - Africa (Box 232, Folder 1)
    - Asia (Folder 2)
    - Australia (Folder 3)
    - Central America (Folder 4)
    - China (Folder 5-6)
    - Far East (Folder 7)
    - Great Britain (Folder 8)
    - India (Folder 9)
    - Indonesia (Folder 10)
    - Japan (Folder 11)
    - Latin America (Folder 12)
    - Middle East (Folder 13)
    - Netherlands (Folder 14)
    - Philippines (Folder 15)
    - Samoa (Folder 16)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 17-18)
    - Spain (Box 233, Folder 1)
    - Taiwan (Folder 2)
    - United States (Folder 3-4)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr (Folder 5)
  - South Asia (Folder 6)
  - Southeast Asia Treaty Organization (SEATO) (Folder 7)
  - Soviet Union
    - General (Folder 8-10)
    - General (Box 234, Folder 1-2)
    - Clippings (Folder 3)
    - History
      - Pre- 1917 (Folder 4-5)
      - Russo-Japanese War, 1905 (Folder 6)
      - Russian Revolution
        - 1905 (Folder 7)
        - 1917 October (Folder 8)
      - Post- 1917 (Box 235, Folder 1-3)
    - Nationalism (Folder 4)
    - Opposition (Folder 5)
  - Spain (Folder 6-7)
  - Spanish Civil War (Folder 8)
  - Spellman, Cardinal (Folder 9)
  - Stalin, Josef (Box 236, Folder 1)
  - Stalin Peace Prize (Folder 2)
  - Stilwell, Joseph (Folder 3)
  - Strasser, Otto (Folder 4)
  - Struve, Peter (Folder 5)
  - Students - Japan (Folder 6)
  - Sun Yat-sen (Folder 7)
  - Switzerland (Folder 8)
  - Taiwan (Folder 9)
  - Taylor, George E. (Folder 10)
  - Technology - China (Folder 11)
  - Terrorism (Folder 12)
  - Thailand. Includes holograph signed letter by King Rama IV (Phra Chom Klao Mongkut), 1855 March 27 (Folder 13)
  - Theology (Folder 14-15)
  - Tibet (Box 237, Folder 1)
  - Tito, Josip Broz (Folder 2)
  - Totalitarianism (Folder 3)
  - Trade
    - Asia (Folder 4)
    - China (Folder 5)
    - Japan (Folder 6)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 7)
  - Transportation - China (Folder 8)
  - Travel
    - China (Folder 9)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 10)
  - Trotsky, Leon
    - General (Folder 11)
    - Writings (Folder 12)
  - Tunisia (Folder 13-14)
  - Turgot, Robert (Box 238, Folder 1)
  - Turkistan (Folder 2)
  - Turkey
    - General (Folder 3)
    - History (Folder 4)
  - United Nations
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Bang-Jensen case (Folder 6)
  - United States
    - General (Folder 7-8)
    - Clippings (Folder 9)
    - History (Folder 10)
  - Unsere Zeit (Folder 11)
  - Varga controversy (Folder 12)
  - Vatican (Folder 13)
  - Vietcong (Folder 14)
  - Vietnam (Folder 15)
  - Vietnam (Box 239, Folder 1-3)
  - Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975 (Folder 4)
  - Voegelin, Eric (Folder 5)
  - Vogt, Carl (Folder 6)
  - Vrangel', Baron Peter (Folder 7)
  - Wagner, Richard
    - Biography (Folder 8-10)
    - Biography (Box 240, Folder 1-7)
    - Biography (Box 241, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence (printed) (Folder 3-4)
  - Wales, Nym (Helen Foster Snow) (Folder 5)
  - Watergate (Folder 6)
  - Weber, Max (Folder 7)
  - Weitling, Wilhelm (Folder 8)
  - Weizsacker, C. F. von (Folder 9)
  - W'eng T'ung-ho (Folder 10)
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth (Folder 11)
  - World Peace Council (Folder 12)
  - World War I - Japan (Folder 13)
  - World War II
    - General (Folder 14)
    - China (Box 242, Folder 1-2)
    - Combatant casualties (Folder 3)
    - Morgenthau Plan (Folder 4)
    - Office of War Information (Folder 5)
    - Pacific Theater (Folder 6)
    - Peace treaty with Japan (Folder 7)
    - Turkey (Folder 8)
    - War crimes (Folder 9)
  - Wu Shu-jen (Folder 10)
  - Yenan (Folder 11)
  - Young Americans for Freedom (Folder 12)
  - Youth
    - Federal Republic of Germany (Folder 13)
    - Japan (Folder 14)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 15)
    - United States (Folder 16)
  - Yugoslavia (Folder 17)
  - Zetkin, Clara (Folder 18)
- CHINESE HISTORY PROJECT, 1936-1977.
  See also OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - General
    - Background of the Chinese History Project (Box 243, Folder 1)
    - Bibliographies (Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1936-1974 (Folder 4)
      - Berman, Ronald, 1973-1975 (Folder 5)
      - Chen, Shou-chiang, 1944-1954 (Folder 6)
      - Chu, Tung-tsu, 1948-1958 (Folder 7)
      - Fu, Lo-shu, 1952-1954 (Folder 8)
      - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1939-1949 (Folder 9)
      - Michael, Franz, 1948-1950 (Folder 10)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1939-1956 (Box 244, Folder 1)
      - Taylor, George E., 1966-1973 (Folder 2)
      - Yu Chuan, 1937 (Folder 3)
    - Financial records. Includes invoices, vouchers, receipts, insurance, budget and related correspondence
      - 1942-1948 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1949-1954 (Folder 6)
      - 1955-1958 (Folder 7)
      - 1959-1965 (Folder 8)
      - 1966-1977 (Folder 9)
    - Guidelines for translation of Chinese sources (Folder 10)
    - Guidelines for translation of Chinese sources (Box 245, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda (Folder 2)
    - Notes
      - General
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Chin dynasty (Folder 4)
        - Ching dynasty (Folder 5)
      - Reading
        - General (Folder 6-8)
        - General (Box 246, Folder 1-6)
        - Shang dynasty (Folder 7)
        - Shang dynasty (Box 247, Folder 1-2)
    - Personnel records (Folder 3)
    - Subject file
      - Anthropology (Folder 4)
      - Feng Chia-sheng (Folder 5)
      - Forced labor (Folder 6-7)
      - K'ang Yu-wei (Folder 8)
      - Marxism Today (Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 10)
      - Shantung rural experiment (Folder 11)
    - Writings
      - Published (Folder 12)
      - Unpublished
        - "From Legends to Proto-History (Hsia)," n.d. Typescript (Folder 13)
        - Hurvitz, Leon, "Recent Japanese Study of Lao-tzu," n.d. Typescript (Folder 14)
        - Ju, Miss, "Development of China's Earliest Stratified Society," n.d. Typescript (Folder 15)
        - Sargent, Clyde Bailey, "Wang Mang: A Translation of the Official Account of His Rise to Power as Given in the History of the Former Han Dynasty", n.d. Typescript (Box 248, Folder 1)
        - "Untersuchungen uber die Ch'un Ch'iu und Warringstates Epoche," n.d. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - Projects and studies
    - Biographical Project. Information gathered was recorded on prepared data sheets arranged by dynasty
      - Dynasties (Folder 3-5)
        - Han
        - Han (Box 249, Folder 1)
        - Chin (Folder 2-5)
        - Tang (Folder 6-7)
        - Tang (Box 250, Folder 1-4)
        - Sung
          - Nan Sung (Folder 5-6)
          - Pei Sung (Folder 7)
        - Sung - Pei Sung (Box 251, Folder 1-6)
        - Sung - Pei Sung (Box 252, Folder 1-3)
        - Yuan (Folder 4-6)
        - Yuan (Box 253, Folder 1)
        - Ming (Folder 2-7)
        - Ming (Box 254, Folder 1-4)
        - Ching (Folder 5-6)
        - Ching (Box 255, Folder 1-6)
        - Ching (Box 256, Folder 1)
      - People's Republic of China (Folder 2-4)
    - Chinese Dynasties History Project. Information gathered was recorded on prepared data sheets arranged chronologically by dynasty
      - Chou, 350-348 B.C. (Folder 5)
        - Chin
        - 361-240 B.C. (Folder 6)
        - 239-214 B.C. (Folder 7)
        - 212-207 B.C. (Folder 8)
      - Han
        - General (Box 257, Folder 1)
        - 206-202 B.C. (Folder 2)
        - 202-179 B.C. (Folder 3)
        - 178-144 B.C. (Folder 4)
        - 143-116 B.C. (Folder 5)
        - 115-70 B.C. (Folder 6)
        - 69-1 B.C. (Folder 7)
        - 1 A.D.-30 (Box 258, Folder 1)
        - 31-79 (Folder 2)
        - 80-110 (Folder 3)
        - 111-166 (Folder 4)
        - 167-220 (Folder 5)
      - Three Kingdoms - Wei, 220-265 (Folder 6)
      - Chin
        - General (Box 259, Folder 1)
        - 265-327 (Folder 2)
        - 328-392 (Folder 3)
        - 393-420 (Folder 4)
      - Southern Dynasties
        - Former Sung
          - 421-434 (Folder 5)
          - 435-460 (Folder 6)
          - 461-479 (Folder 7)
        - Southern Chi, 479-502 (Box 260, Folder 1)
        - Southern Liang
          - 502-537 (Folder 2)
          - 538-556 (Folder 3)
        - Southern Chen, 557-589 (Folder 4)
      - Northern Dynasties
        - Northern Wei
          - 386-432 (Folder 5)
          - 433-471 (Folder 6)
          - 472-487 (Folder 7)
          - 488-510 (Box 261, Folder 1)
          - 511-528 (Folder 2)
          - 529-533 (Folder 3)
        - Eastern Wei, 534-549 (Folder 4)
        - Western Wei, 535-556 (Folder 5)
        - Northern Chou
          - 550-576 (Folder 6)
          - 557-581 (Folder 7)
      - Sui
        - 581-609 (Folder 8)
        - 609-618 (Box 262, Folder 1)
      - Tang
        - General (Folder 2)
        - 618-639 (Folder 3)
        - 640-680 (Folder 4)
        - 681-712 (Folder 5)
        - 713-741 (Folder 6)
        - 742-764 (Folder 7)
        - 765-783 (Box 263, Folder 1)
        - 784-810 (Folder 2)
        - 811-826 (Folder 3)
        - 827-852 (Folder 4)
        - 853-880 (Folder 5)
        - 881-908 (Box 264, Folder 1)
      - Five Dynasties
        - Liang, 906-923 (Folder 2)
        - Tang, 924-936 (Folder 3)
        - Chin, 937-947 (Folder 4)
        - Han, 948-950 (Folder 5)
        - Chou, 951-959 (Folder 6)
      - Liao
        - 907-918 (Folder 7)
        - 919-941 (Folder 8)
        - 942-973 (Folder 9)
        - 974-999 (Box 265, Folder 1)
        - 1000-1030 (Folder 2)
        - 1031-1062 (Folder 3)
        - 1080-1097 (Folder 4)
        - 1098-1125 (Folder 5)
      - Sung
        - General (Box 266, Folder 1)
        - 960-964 (Folder 2)
        - 965-975 (Folder 3)
        - 976-981 (Folder 4)
        - 982-989 (Folder 5)
        - 990-996 (Folder 6)
        - 997-1003 (Folder 7)
        - 1004-1011 (Box 267, Folder 1)
        - 1012-1023 (Folder 2)
        - 1024-1039 (Folder 3)
        - 1040-1049 (Folder 4)
        - 1050-1065 (Folder 5)
        - 1066-1070 (Box 268, Folder 1)
        - 1071-1076 (Folder 2)
        - 1077-1081 (Folder 3)
        - 1082-1091 (Folder 4)
        - 1092-1101 (Folder 5)
        - 1102-1107 (Folder 6)
        - 1108-1123 (Box 269, Folder 1)
        - 1124-1131 (Folder 2)
        - 1132-1140 (Folder 3)
        - 1141-1159 (Folder 4)
        - 1160-1169 (Box 270, Folder 1)
        - 1170-1183 (Folder 2)
        - 1184-1202 (Folder 3)
        - 1203-1220 (Folder 4)
        - 1221-1249 (Folder 5)
        - 1250-1279 (Folder 6)
      - House of Chin
        - 1115-1185 (Box 271, Folder 1)
        - 1185-1235 (Folder 2)
      - Yuan
        - General (Folder 3)
        - 1207-1260 (Folder 4)
        - 1261-1266 (Folder 5)
        - 1267-1274 (Folder 6)
        - 1275-1280 (Box 272, Folder 1)
        - 1280 (Folder 2-3)
        - 1281-1285 (Folder 4)
        - 1286-1289 (Folder 5)
        - 1290-1292 (Box 273, Folder 1)
        - 1293-1296 (Folder 2)
        - 1297-1303 (Folder 3)
        - 1304-1308 (Folder 4)
        - 1308-1311 (Box 274, Folder 1)
        - 1312-1317 (Folder 2)
        - 1318-1321 (Folder 3)
        - 1321-1324 (Folder 4)
        - 1325-1327 (Box 275, Folder 1)
        - 1327-1328 (Folder 2)
        - 1328-1332 (Folder 3)
        - 1333-1342 (Folder 4)
        - 1343-1352 (Folder 5)
        - 1352-1356 (Box 276, Folder 1)
        - 1357-1365 (Folder 2)
        - 1366-1368 (Folder 3)
      - Ming
        - General (Folder 4)
        - 1368-1381 (Folder 5)
        - 1382-1396 (Folder 6)
        - 1397-1411 (Folder 7)
        - 1412-1432 (Box 277, Folder 1)
        - 1433-1448 (Folder 2)
        - 1449-1460 (Folder 3)
        - 1461-1481 (Folder 4)
        - 1482-1497 (Folder 5)
        - 1498-1512 (Folder 6)
        - 1513-1528 (Box 278, Folder 1)
        - 1529-1552 (Folder 2)
        - 1553-1571 (Folder 3)
        - 1572-1587 (Folder 4)
        - 1588-1602 (Folder 5)
        - 1603-1621 (Box 279, Folder 1)
        - 1622-1631 (Folder 2)
        - 1632-1644 (Folder 3)
      - Ching
        - General (Folder 4)
        - 1626-1644 (Folder 5)
        - 1645-1646 (Folder 6)
        - 1647-1658 (Box 280, Folder 1)
        - 1659-1674 (Folder 2)
        - 1675-1698 (Folder 3)
        - 1699-1723 (Folder 4)
        - 1724-1736 (Folder 5)
        - 1737-1750 (Box 281, Folder 1)
        - 1751-1762 (Folder 2)
        - 1763-1777 (Folder 3)
        - 1778-1791 (Folder 4)
        - 1792-1805 (Folder 5)
        - 1806-1821 (Folder 6)
        - 1822-1835 (Box 282, Folder 1)
        - 1837-1848 (Folder 2)
        - 1848-1862 (Folder 3)
        - 1863-1871 (Folder 4)
        - 1872-1883 (Folder 5)
        - 1884-1895 (Folder 1)
        - 1896-1904 (Folder 2)
        - 1905-1911 (Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 4)
      - Notes
        - General (Folder 5)
        - Reading
          - Agriculture (Box 284, Folder 1)
          - Twenty-four dynasties (Folder 2)
          - 990-223 B.C. (Folder 3-4)
    - Chinese Family Study. Includes notes and copies of questionnaires distributed among Chinese students (Folder 5-6)
    - Ch'in-Han Project
      - General. Includes miscellaneous notes, memoranda, progress reports, and outlines (Box 285, Folder 1-3)
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Ellison, Herbert Jay, 1972-1973 (Folder 5)
        - Lo, Jung-pang, 1957-1961 (Folder 6)
        - Wilhelm, Hellmut, 1957-1973 (Folder 7)
      - "The Art of War in the Ch'in and Han Periods: 221 B.C.-A.D. 220." Typescript (Folder 8)
      - Typescript of Ch'in-Han Project
        - Introduction (Folder 9)
        - I (Folder 10)
        - II (Folder 11)
        - III (Folder 12)
        - IV (Box 286, Folder 1)
        - V (Folder 2)
        - VI (Folder 3)
        - VII (Folder 4)
        - VIII (Folder 5)
    - Reprint Series Project (Folder 6-8)
- CHINESE LANGUAGE MATERIALS, n.d.
  - (unsorted) (Box 287-290)
- ESTHER SCHIFF GOLDFRANK PAPERS (KAW's third wife), 1917-1987
  - General (Box 291, Folder 1)
  - Biographical file
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Articles and clippings about Esther S. Goldfrank (Folder 3)
    - Awards and honors (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence file, 1922-1980
    - General. Includes cards from family members (Folder 5)
    - Babcock, Barbara (Folder 6)
    - Benedict, Ruth (Folder 7)
    - Dozier, Edward (Folder 8)
    - Parsons, Elsie Clews (Folder 9)
    - Sack, Ellen (Folder 10)
  - Instructions to executors regarding the disposition of Esther S. Goldfrank's papers upon her death (Folder 11)
  - Speeches and writings
    - Bibliography
      - General (Folder 12)
      - "The Times Between"
        - Correspondence (Folder 13)
        - Typescript, ca. 1973 (Folder 14)
    - Notes (Folder 15)
    - Published writings
      - General (Folder 16)
      - General (Box 292, Folder 1)
      - Notes on an Undirected Life, 1978
        - Correspondence
          - General (Folder 2)
          - Copies of Franz Boas' correspondence and notes (Folder 3-5)
        - Notes (Folder 6-7)
        - Reviews (Box 293, Folder 1)
  - Travel notes and schedules
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Japan, 1957 (Folder 3)
- GARY L. ULMEN PAPERS, 1964-1986
  - General (Box 294, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General. Includes miscellaneous letters about Gary L. Ulmen (Folder 2)
    - Lang, Olga (Folder 3)
    - Treadgold, Donald W. (Folder 4)
  - Writings
    - General
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Notes (Folder 6)
      - Printed articles (Folder 7)
      - Reviews by Gary L. Ulmen (Folder 8)
    - "An Anarchism or Communism in China," n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
    - "Early Soviet Agricultural Experiments, 1918-1920," 1965. Master thesis (Folder 10)
    - "Economy and Society in Russia," n.d. Typescript (Folder 11)
    - "Footnotes and Other Follies," 1984 June. Typescript (Folder 12)
    - "Memoranda on Karl August Wittfogel," n.d. Typescript (Folder 13)
    - "On Ivan Kirieevskiis: 'The Nineteenth Century,'" 1967. Report submitted to Professor Marc Raeff (Folder 14)
    - Science of Society, 1978
      - General. Includes contract, correspondence, and excerpts, 1975-1979 (Folder 15)
      - Reviews, 1979-1982 (Folder 16)
    - Society and History, 1978. Contract and book reviews (Folder 17)
    - "Sociology of the State: Carl Schmidt and Max Weber," n.d. Typescript (Box 295, Folder 1)
    - "Synopsis of Nacismo: The Rise and Fall of National Socialism in Chile, 1932-1938," n.d. Typescript (Folder 2)
    - "Toward a 'New Leviathan': Power in the Postwar World," n.d. Typescript (Folder 3)
    - "Wittfogel at 90," 1986 September 6. Typescript (Folder 4)
    - "Zu einer neuen Wissenschaft der Gesellschaft," n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
- INDEX CARD FILE, n.d.
  - Address file (Box 296-298)
  - Bibliographic file. In general arranged alphabetically by author
    - General (Box 298-303)
    - Chinese (Box 304)
  - Chinese biographies name file (Box 305)
  - Reference note file. Arranged alphabetically by author (Box 306)
- Sound recordings (PHONOTAPE REELS), 1966
  - Sound recordings of KAW's memoirs. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, Memoirs, 1966, for a transcript (Box 307-309, Tape Tapes 1-31.)
  - German folk music (Box 309, Tape Tape 32.)
- MICROFILM REELS, 1832-1938
  - Asiatic mode of production (Reel 1)
  - Chinese revolution, 1911 (Reel 2)